<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Arjun9124's Updates Rss Feed</title>
<description>My Updates RSS feed.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>http://arjun9124.github.io/updates.xml</link>
<atom:link href="http://arjun9124.github.io/updates.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- SUP -->

<item>
<title>Photo 04-03-2023</title>
<pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 07:29:16 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<div style="max-width :90%"><img src="files/tree030423.jpg" width="90%"></div>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>What to do in life</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 07:58:17 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[I dont have to figure out what to do in life, I just have to figure out how do I kill time untill I find what to do.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>ENDLESS RAIN</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 17:59:01 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Perpetual rain, on the homepage. <br> <a href="https://invidious.snopyta.org/watch?v=IJJyItJndK8">[rain]</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>No more page view counter, A dedicated updates/musings page</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 17:30:48 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[I removed the view counter as it used to take hold of the page focus and redirect to some adverts as soon as the user clicked the page. Also I added a dedicated links page <a href="/updates.html">here</a> So that people can view the updates and musings in a better way, so yeah now we have a dedicated cheapo ripoff brokeass twitter copy.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Cluttered Households, Depressed Grandmothers</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 07:09:53 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<i>Cluttered households are merely victimes of consumerism.</i><br> Victims of consumerism that could not cope with it. Consuming too much to be clean, consuming to little to be minimalist <br>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Jab the eyes</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 08:00:55 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Gouge them out, eyeballs. <br> Someone tries to beat you up gouge them out. Lobotomize them.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Back to the old website</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2023 06:42:28 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[With a will that shall bring end to all careerism, I ascend to this webpage to claim whats rightfully mine. What was I doing back there, no man thats not how things are done, back to the old webpage. I hope that the other one is forgotten with time.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Why didn't I learn CSS Grid and Flexbox before ?</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 11:11:24 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[After months of having wonky broken div's, boxes and elements on my webpage I finally learnt CSS Grid and Flexbox. HTML's never been better. <br>Folks, better learn flexbox and grid if you dont know it. LEARN IT NOW. Its a boon to mankind.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Second thoughts on Hugo</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 18:11:56 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[yeah hugos great and all but this html page with the bash scripts isnt bad either I dont think I'll be swithing too soon.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Back to the old webpage</title>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 09:31:53 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Well, the Hugo webpage did come off great and works like a charm but its going to take me a while to deploy it to github pages. <br> Hence, coming back to the old ways.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>What 'masturbation is to sex' is what 'memes are to comedy'</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 06 Aug 2022 10:19:24 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://iwiwly.substack.com/p/ha-ha-orgasm-ha-ha-purge">....Funny memes as comedy is masturbation. Masturbation being a clever monkey manipulation for the mechanic orgasm. Old comedy–stand up and the subtler social performances before that–were more akin to sex, still mechanic, sometimes mechanic-spiritual but a cathartic back and forth....</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Bye Bye Rolling blog page</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 10:49:46 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[I found the rolling blog page to be very irritating and decided to replace it with the blog index.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Vice: A Series of Forgotten Photos Capture What Life Was Like in 1980s India</title>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 10:57:09 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/epx3bn/nostalgic-photos-art-bombay-delhi-india-1980s">......The year was 1978. India was reeling from a decade of brutal war, political turmoil and economic unrest. Even so, the streets were alive with the collision of people from all walks of life. Decadent cabaret striptease clubs were all the rage. Religious festivals brought out a jubilant sense of community, even though the societal fabric was frayed by extreme inequalities.....</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The Internet Is Dead [Video Essay]</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 08:48:55 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[The Dead Internet Theory by All Time on YouTube. <a href="https://piped.kavin.rocks/watch?v=DEn758DVF9I">[Watch Here]</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Papercraft: Star Trek NCC-1701 USS Enterprise Paper Model [FREE TEMPLATE]</title>
<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:43:53 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[https://forjapapel.blogspot.com/2022/05/papercraft-star-trek-uss-enterprise.html <br> A free paper model of the USS Enterprise from Star Trek by forjapapel. Shall be making this in the future.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Article: Hotel Staffers Tell Us the Weirdest Things They Have Seen Rich People Do</title>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 17:15:10 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://www.vice.com/en/article/4awbzm/weird-demands-rich-wealthy-people-in-luxury-best-hotels">....."The horse had to follow him everywhere, whether he was eating or shitting. It was only on the second or third day that we found out he had developed an unhealthy, almost sexual, infatuation towards the horse." .....</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Updates RSS Feed Fixed</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:22:25 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Fixed the Updates RSS feed. Didnt close some tags lol
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Guestbook</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:25:42 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[A guestbook for the website, and maybe a webpage view meter as well.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><a href="https://empiresoflight.blogspot.com/2022/04/grinding-soul-into-dust-extracurricular.html">Grinding the soul into dust: Extracurricular activites in Indian schools</a></title>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:23:55 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[ ....Rather than enable spontaneous but restrained self expression, they were compelled to robotically make hand gestures at particular phrases and artificial pauses (an old radio trick for dramatic emphasis).....  Might as well call them currycular activites]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>New morning theme !</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[New morning theme added. Taking us to a total of 4 themes. Yeah right, talk of minimal now !
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>Timed CSS Themes Added!</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Time dependenent pixel art themes have been added to the webpage. I hope you all like them.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The one nation, one language fallacy</title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/opinion/columns/the-one-nation-one-language-fallacy-7894218/">Mrinal Kaul writes: India has never done justice to its linguistic diversity or focused on quality language learning. Languages, instead, have become instruments of exercising hegemony.</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>No one can be forced to get vaccinated… Centre’s current policy not arbitrary: SC</title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/supreme-court-centre-covid-19-vaccine-policy-7897266/">....Upholding an individual’s right to bodily integrity and to refuse to get medically treated, the court said that “no individual can be forced to be vaccinated” but added that “in the interest of protection of communitarian health, the government is entitled to regulate issues of public health concern by imposing certain limitations.”....</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>Some GIF's Added</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[So lets get some old web energy flowing with these retro-ey gifs
]]></description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
