<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="rss.css" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<channel>
<title>Arjun9124's Updates Rss Feed</title>
<description>My Updates RSS feed.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>http://arjun9124.github.io/updates.xml</link>
<atom:link href="http://arjun9124.github.io/updates.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<!-- SUP -->

<item>
<title>Updates RSS Feed Fixed</title>
<pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:22:25 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Fixed the Updates RSS feed. Didnt close some tags lol
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>Guestbook</title>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 14:25:42 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[A guestbook for the website, and maybe a webpage view meter as well.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><a href="https://empiresoflight.blogspot.com/2022/04/grinding-soul-into-dust-extracurricular.html">Grinding the soul into dust: Extracurricular activites in Indian schools</a></title>
<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 13:23:55 +0530</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[ ....Rather than enable spontaneous but restrained self expression, they were compelled to robotically make hand gestures at particular phrases and artificial pauses (an old radio trick for dramatic emphasis).....  Might as well call them currycular activites]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>New morning theme !</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[New morning theme added. Taking us to a total of 4 themes. Yeah right, talk of minimal now !
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>Timed CSS Themes Added!</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[Time dependenent pixel art themes have been added to the webpage. I hope you all like them.
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>The one nation, one language fallacy</title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/opinion/columns/the-one-nation-one-language-fallacy-7894218/">Mrinal Kaul writes: India has never done justice to its linguistic diversity or focused on quality language learning. Languages, instead, have become instruments of exercising hegemony.</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title>No one can be forced to get vaccinated… Centre’s current policy not arbitrary: SC</title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[<a href="https://indianexpress.com/article/india/supreme-court-centre-covid-19-vaccine-policy-7897266/">....Upholding an individual’s right to bodily integrity and to refuse to get medically treated, the court said that “no individual can be forced to be vaccinated” but added that “in the interest of protection of communitarian health, the government is entitled to regulate issues of public health concern by imposing certain limitations.”....</a>
]]></description>
</item>


<item>
<title><strong>Some GIF's Added</strong></title>
<pubDate></pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[So lets get some old web energy flowing with these retro-ey gifs
]]></description>
</item>


</channel>
</rss>
